<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>named entity recognition on Saumya Shah</title>
    <link>https://shahsaumya.github.io/tags/named-entity-recognition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in named entity recognition on Saumya Shah</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shahsaumya.github.io/tags/named-entity-recognition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Probate Parsing</title>
      <link>https://shahsaumya.github.io/projects/contributions/probate_parsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahsaumya.github.io/projects/contributions/probate_parsing/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to work on projects that would benefit society and found Google Summer of Code (GSoC) to be the perfect opportunity. I worked with Free UK Genealogy, an organization that aims at the transcription of family data and explored Named Entity Recognition (NER) more deeply. I created an end-to-end framework that extracts text from wills, using OCR, and seeds them into a database with named entities. A big constraint in the project was a lack of adequate training samples to build an accurate NER model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family History Extraction using Clinical Narratives</title>
      <link>https://shahsaumya.github.io/publications/bionlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahsaumya.github.io/publications/bionlp/</guid>
      <description>For my graduation project, I worked with Prof. Meliha Yetisgen as a graduate research assistant in the BioNLP lab and worked on a project that aimed at extracting family history from patients’ clinical narratives. The project required me to develop an end-to-end system from preparing the training dataset for the individual tasks to selecting the model, algorithm, and implementation.
This project can be divided into two main subtasks:
• Entity identification (family members and disease names) - This involves getting the family members and disease names (unassociated).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>