<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Natural Language Processing on Saumya Shah</title>
    <link>https://shahsaumya.github.io/tags/natural-language-processing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Natural Language Processing on Saumya Shah</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shahsaumya.github.io/tags/natural-language-processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Family History Extraction using Clinical Narratives</title>
      <link>https://shahsaumya.github.io/publications/bionlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahsaumya.github.io/publications/bionlp/</guid>
      <description>For my graduation project, I worked with Prof. Meliha Yetisgen as a graduate research assistant in the BioNLP lab and worked on a project that aimed at extracting family history from patients’ clinical narratives. The project required me to develop an end-to-end system from preparing the training dataset for the individual tasks to selecting the model, algorithm, and implementation.
This project can be divided into two main subtasks:
• Entity identification (family members and disease names) - This involves getting the family members and disease names (unassociated).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Question Generation and Answer Verification using Visual Data</title>
      <link>https://shahsaumya.github.io/publications/automated-vqg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahsaumya.github.io/publications/automated-vqg/</guid>
      <description>This paper delineates the automation of question generation as an extension to existing Visual Question Answering (VQA) systems. Through our research, we have been able to build a system that can generate questions and answer pairs on images. It consists of two separate modules - Visual Question Generation (VQG) which generates questions based on the image, and a Visual Question Answering (VQA) module that produces a befitting answer that the VQG module generates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Question Generation and Answer Verification using Digital Data</title>
      <link>https://shahsaumya.github.io/projects/creations/automated_vqg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahsaumya.github.io/projects/creations/automated_vqg/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, we have witnessed a significant progress in various fields of AI, such as computer vision, as well as language understanding. These progress motivated researchers to address a more challenging problem: question answering and question generation on visual data. This problem combines both image understanding as well as language understanding. Essentially, this task is defined as follows: an image along with a question about that image is the input to the AI system, and the intelligent system is supposed to output a correct answer to the question with respect the input image.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>